Jessica. &gt;&gt; Hm?
— Jessica — 嗯？
We need to talk.
我们需要谈谈
&gt;&gt; What? What's up?
说什么？发生了什么？
&gt;&gt; We've been hand-holding them way too much, and it has got to stop.
我们一直都是在手把手地教大家 现在必须要停止这么做了
&gt;&gt; What? &gt;&gt; Okay,
— 什么？— 嗯
we've been in the kiddie pool for way too long.
我们待在儿童泳池里太长时间了
We've been giving them all these instructions,
我们一直都为学员提供各种说明
telling them what to do next.
告诉他们下一步该怎么操作
But then when they're out in the real world working on their own project,
但是当他们在现实生活中完成自己的项目时
they're going to get stuck.
他们就会遇到挫折
They're not going to know what to do next.
他们不知道下一步该怎么办
And when they're in the deep end, they might drown.
当他们进入深水区的时候 他们可能会淹死
You don't want them to drown, right?
你不希望他们淹死吧？
Whoa, whoa, whoa, that's super extreme.
等等 说的太极端了
All right, so let's compromise.
好吧 折中一下
So how bout for the next feature of adding images to the app we'll help them
对于下一个向应用中添加图片的任务 要不我们
by thinking of strategies to execute and then what orders to execute those in.
帮助学员思考要执行的策略 以及按照什么顺序来执行这些策略
&gt;&gt; Okay.
— 好的
I could see that working out.
这么做可行
But no more hand holding after that.
但是不要再手把手地教了
&gt;&gt; All right, so we've come to a key point in every developer's workflow.
— 好的 我们进入了每个开发者工作流程的关键阶段
The app is functioning and it tells the users about the Miwok translations for
应用可以正常运转 并告诉用户英语单词
the English words.
对应的米沃克语翻译
Now a feature request has come in to add images to the app, and we discussed it
现在出现了一个功能请求 即向应用中添加图片
with our designer, and this is what we'd like the app to look like.
与设计师讨论过后 我们希望应用的外观是这样的
So if you're on a team it's common for
如果你是团队成员
you as a developer to take on a single feature, like adding images to the app.
作为开发者 经常你需要负责一项功能 例如向应用中添加图片
It's also common for a Program Manager or Tech Lead of your team to ask you for
而且项目经理或技术主管经常还会要求你
a time estimate of how long it'll take you to build out a feature.
估算下构建某个功能需要花费的时间
So I won't ask you for a time estimate.
我不会请你估算时间
But I do want you to estimate the scope of your work.
但是却需要你估算下工作范围
So at a high level, what changes to the app needs to be made?
从更高层面来说 需要对应用做出什么更改？
So you may be thinking, I understand what we need to achieve and
你可能会想 我知道我们需要实现什么目标
why, but I'm not sure the next steps to get there.
以及理由是什么 但是不确定后续步骤
And I'm not even sure how to determine the scope of the work.
甚至不知道如何判断工作范围
Well all those thoughts are perfectly normal and
所有这些想法都是正常现象
that's why we're here to help.
这也就是为何我们会提供帮助
So one of the first things we can do to plan is to make sure we have
我们可以计划的第一项内容是确保
a mental map of our code base.
有一个仓库蓝图
And review how everything fits together.
看看所有内容是如何相吻合的
So you may have noticed, our code has gotten quite complex.
你可能注意到了 我们的代码已经非常复杂
There's multiple layout files, a few Java files, and
有多个布局文件 几个 Java 文件
a couple more resources as well.
还有几个资源
So using a mental model, we can peer into our code and anticipate and
借助蓝图 我们可以观察下代码
visualize all the medications that we'll need to make
预测并画出需要对仓库的不同部分
to the different parts of the code base.
进行的修改
Depending on the feature it could mean affecting many different files.
根据具体的功能 可能会影响到很多不同的文件
So having a mental map will help us anticipate
所以绘制蓝图可以帮助我们预测
where we'll need to make changes.
需要在什么地方做出更改
So let's revisit our mental diagram from lesson one.
再来看看第一节课中的蓝图
We filled out a lot more features since then, and
从第一节课开始 我们添加了越来越多的功能
we've made some modifications to it slightly.
并且稍微做出了一些修改
Now there's no rules for how to create a proper mental model
并没有特定的规则限定如何创建恰当的蓝图
as long as you can keep track of all the major parts of the app.
只要能追踪应用的各大主要部分即可
So since the app is getting more complex we can zoom out a bit,
应用已经很复杂 我们可以稍微放大下
meaning we don't have to include all the details that we originally had.
意味着不用包含之前包含的所有详细信息
So we know that they're still there but they're just not at the top of our mind.
我们知道这些详细信息依然存在 只是在我们的脑海中已经不是首要信息了
So currently this is a model of our app flow so
目前这是我们的应用流程模型
tapping on each category takes us to the appropriate activity.
点按每个类别可以使我们转到相应的 Activity
We've also taken a look at how each activity, gets and
同时 我们研究了每个 Activity 如何获取
displays the appropriate data.
并显示相应的数据
So let's focus in on the numbers activity.
我们来看看 NumbersActivity
We store data in word objects inside an array list.
我们将 Word 对象中的数据存储在数组列表中
And retrieved and display that information
我们使用 ListView 和数组适配器
in each list item using the list view and array adapter combination.
来检索并显示每个列表项中的信息
So in the next node you'll see the two diagrams of our current mental
在下一个节点 你将看到当前应用蓝图的
model of the app.
两个图表
So to help us scope out our new feature of adding images to each word,
为了帮助我们确定为每个单词添加图片这一新功能的范围
what changes will we need to make to each of the two diagrams?
我们需要对这两个图表做出哪些更改？
Now assume that the phrases activity will not be showing images,
假设 PhrasesActivity 不会显示图片
and will be a special case that will be handled later.
并且稍后会处理这一特殊情形
So ignore that difference for now.
暂时先忽略了
Now remember this is a thought exercise to help you began planning
注意 这是一道思考练习题 可以帮助你
how you'll build out your next feature.
规划如何构建下一个功能
So there's no right or wrong answer.
所以没有正确或错误答案
And when you're done,
完成后
I'd like you check this box when you've sketched out your potential solutions.
当你绘制出可能的解决方案后 请选中该方框